answersingenesis.org 2018-09-03

# Privacy Policy | Answers in Genesis

The Answers in Genesis Privacy Policy outlines the information that Answers in Genesis gathers, how we use that information, and the options you have to access, correct, or delete such information.

## Our Commitment

Answers in Genesis is committed to respecting the privacy and rights of all parties who interact with the ministry, including our donors. We deeply appreciate that you’ve trusted us with your personal information, and we are committed to treating it confidentially.

The following outlines our Privacy Policy and details the measures we have taken to safeguard and protect your privacy. Here we describe the privacy practices for our applications, software, websites, APIs, products, and services (the “Services”). You will learn about the data we collect, how we use it, the controls we give you over your information, and the measures we take to keep it safe. Specifically, we’ll cover:

  * Information We Collect
  * How We Use Information We Collect
  * How Information Is Shared
  * Your Access to and Control of Personal Data
  * Data Retention
  * Analytics and Advertising Services Provided by Others
  * Our Policy on Children
  * Information Security
  * International Information Transfers
  * Changes to this Policy
  * Who We Are and How to Contact Us

## Information We Collect

On our websites, you can provide contact information for ministry-related purposes, to order resources, to receive updates and promotions by mail and by email, or to make ministry contributions. When you use our Services, we collect the following types of information:

  * Contact Information: Name, organization, complete address, phone, email address. 
  * Payment Information: Method of payment, credit card or service ID, essential verification information. 
  * Shipping Information: Name, organization, complete shipping address, and phone number. 
  * Promotional Information: How you found us, what prompted your interest, and your areas of interest. 
  * Survey Information: Contact information and demographics such as postal/zip code, age level, educational background, website preferences, etc. 
  * Correspondence Information: Suggestions, comments, messages, questions, and requests for further correspondence. 
  * Usage Information: IP address, browser type, operating system, date stamps, etc. (see Logs below). 

### Information You Provide

#### Account Information

Some information is required to create an account on our Services, such as your name, email address, and password. This is the only information you have to provide to create an account with us. You may also choose to provide other types of information, such as country information, date of birth, gender, and phone number. If you contact us or participate in a survey, contest, or promotion, we collect the information you submit such as your name, contact information, and message.

#### Information from Third-Party Services

If you choose to connect your account on our Services to your account on another service, we may receive information from the other service. For example, if you connect to Facebook or Google, we may receive information like your name, profile picture, age range, language, email address, and friend list. You may also choose to grant us access to your data from another service. You can stop sharing the information from the other service with us by removing our access to that other service.

#### Payment and Card Information

Answers in Genesis complies with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard that requires us to provide certain data security measures in order to, among other things:

  * Protect cardholder data that is stored
  * Have and maintain a firewall configuration
  * Maintain industry standard password complexity requirements
  * Encrypt transmission of cardholder data across public networks
  * Restrict access to cardholder data by business need-to-know
  * Track access to network resources
  * Regularly test security systems and processes

If you purchase Answers in Genesis merchandise on our website, you provide your payment information, including your name, credit or debit card number, card expiration date, CVV code, and billing address. We do not store any sensitive payment information, but your name and billing address are stored to process your order. We also store your shipping address to fulfill your order. Note that third-party payment processors may retain this information in accordance with their own privacy policies and terms.

### Information We Receive from Your Use of Our Services

When you access or use our Services, we receive certain usage data. This includes information about your interaction with the Services, for example, when you view or search content, install applications or software, create or log into your account, or open or interact with an application on your device.

We also collect data about the devices and computers you use to access the Services, including IP addresses, browser type, language, operating system, or mobile device information (including device and application identifiers), the referring web page, pages visited, location (depending on the permissions you have granted us), and cookie information.

### Legal Basis for Collecting and Processing Personal Data of European Customers (GDPR)

If you are an individual from the European Economic Area (EEA) and your transaction is subject to the European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), your Services will generally be handled by Answers in Genesis-UK/Europe. In the event the U.S. ministry receives Service requests from European residents, we will generally refer your Service request to the UK ministry for processing, unless the particular Service requested is not available through the UK ministry or can only be provided or processed through the U.S. ministry.

In the event the U.S. ministry does receive personal data of European customers, please note that our legal basis for collecting and using your personal information will depend on the personal information collected and the specific context in which we collect it. We normally will collect personal information from you only where: (a) we have your consent to do so, (b) where we need your personal information to perform a contract with you (e.g., to deliver the Services you have requested), or (c) where the processing is in our legitimate interests. Please note that in most cases, if you do not provide the requested information, Answers in Genesis will not be able to provide the requested service to you.

In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you or may otherwise need the personal information to protect your vital interests or those of another person.

Where we rely on your consent to process your personal data, you have the right to withdraw or decline consent at any time. Where we rely on our legitimate interests to process your personal data, you have the right to object.

If you have any questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information, please contact us.

## How We Use Information We Collect

We use the information we collect for the following purposes:

### Provide and Maintain the Services

By using the information we collect, we are able to deliver the Services and honor our contract with you, and we use your information to give you customer support.

### Improve, Personalize, and Develop the Services

We use the information we collect to improve and personalize the Services and to develop new ones. For example, we use the information to troubleshoot and protect against errors; perform data analysis and testing; conduct research and surveys; and develop new features and Services. We also use your information for profiling our users in order to show you more relevant content.

### Communicate with You

We use your information when needed to send you Service notifications and respond to you when you contact us. We also use your information to send you relevant content, provide ministry updates, and to promote resources and products you may be interested in. You can control marketing communications by using the “change your subscriptions” or “opt out of all emails” links in our emails.

### Promote Safety and Security

We use the information we collect to promote the safety and security of the Services, our users, and other parties. For example, we may use the information to authenticate users, facilitate secure payments, protect against fraud and abuse, respond to a legal request or claim, conduct audits, and enforce our terms and policies.

### Logs

Answers in Genesis uses log files to track trends, activity, and improve the overall user experience. These log files contain information about what domain you are coming from (i.e., AOL.com, Google.com), what browser software and system software you use, and what pages were visited on our site. This information is shared among Answers in Genesis employees, leadership, and select vendors and is archived for analysis in the future. Some anonymous browsing data may be shared publicly for promotional purposes.

### Cookies

We use cookies and similar technologies to give you a better customer experience. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser to enable our systems to recognize your browser and improve your experience by providing features for our Services, including our online stores.

The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to change how your browser handles cookies. However, cookies allow you to take full advantage of our website and the vast majority of others, and we recommend that you leave them turned on.

The Kids Answers section of AnswersInGenesis.org uses cookies and similar elements to give you and your kids a better experience.

We use Google Analytics to track visits to all of our webpages, including on the Kids section of AnswersInGenesis.org. This service provides us anonymous user information that helps identify visitor trends so we can continue to improve our websites and Services.

### Our Use of Information from European Subjects

For European customers whose personal data is received by us and is subject to the GDPR, we rely on several legal bases to process the data. These include when you have given your consent, which you may withdraw at any time by using the “opt out of all emails” link in our emails or by contacting us; when the processing is necessary to perform a contract with you; and our legitimate business interests, such as assisting our affiliate in the U.K. with a Service request, or in improving, personalizing, and developing the Services, delivering email and printed newsletters, marketing new features or products that may be of interest, profiling to better understand our users, and promoting safety and security, as described above.

## How Information Is Shared

We do not share your personal information except in the limited circumstances described below.

### For External Processing

We transfer information to our corporate affiliates, service providers, and other partners who process it for us, based on our instructions, and in compliance with this policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures. These partners provide us with services globally, including for customer support, information technology, payments, sales, marketing, data analysis, research, and surveys. We also share your information with our data processing partners, such as MailChimp, Constant Contact, Facebook, Google, and Joseph David Advertising, to facilitate our Services. For donation-related Services we may share information with HSP Direct, BBS & Associates, and iDonate.

### For Legal or Security Reasons

We may preserve or disclose information about you to comply with a law, regulation, legal process, or governmental request; to assert legal rights or defend against legal claims; or to prevent, detect, or investigate illegal activity, fraud, abuse, violations of our terms, or threats to the security of the Services.

We may share non-personal information that is aggregated, anonymous or de-identified so that it cannot reasonably be used to identify an individual. We may disclose such information publicly and to third parties, for example, in public reports about attendance at ministry venues or events, to partners under agreement with us, or as part of the community benchmarking information we provide to users of our subscription services.

## Your Access to and Control of Personal Data

If you live in the European Economic Area (EU member countries and Iceland, Liechtenstein, and Norway), or in the United Kingdom, or Switzerland, you have certain legal rights with respect to your personal information This includes the right to access, correct, update, export, or delete your personal information.

If you need assistance regarding your rights, please contact us, and we will consider your request in accordance with applicable laws.

If you request to delete your account and other subject data, please note that while most of your information will be deleted within 30 days, it may take up to 90 days to delete all of your information, like the data stored in our backup systems. This is due to the size and complexity of the systems we use to store data. We may also preserve data for legal security reasons, including as described in the How Information is Shared section.

## Data Retention

We keep your account information, like your name, email address, and password, for as long as your account is in existence because we need it to operate your account. In some cases, when you give us information for a feature of the Services, we delete the data after it is no longer needed for the feature. We keep other information indefinitely unless you request its removal because we use this data to provide you with information and updates on our Services. We also keep information about you and your use of the Services for as long as necessary for our legitimate business interests, for legal reasons, and to prevent harm, including as described in the How We Use Information and How Information is Shared sections.

## Analytics and Advertising Services Provided by Others

We work with partners who provide us with analytics and advertising services, including Google Analytics, Facebook, and Joseph David Advertising. This includes helping us understand how users interact with the Services, serving ads on our behalf across the internet, and measuring the performance of those ads. These companies may use cookies and similar technologies to collect information about your interactions with the Services and other websites and applications. To learn more and about your privacy choices, please read our Cookies statement.

## Our Policy on Children

We appreciate the importance of taking additional measures to protect children’s privacy. Our Services at Answers in Genesis are not directed to children under the age of 13, with the exception of the “Kids Answers” section of AnswersInGenesis.org, which provides content and activities specifically for children. No personally identifiable data is collected from or about children using this section of the website intended for them. We offer a “kids mode” to allow younger children to safely use this section of our website with their parent or guardian’s help and supervision, and without requiring any personal information from the children. In addition, to the extent that children participate in our Vacation Bible School programs, parents may be requested to provide basic registration information for such purpose.

We do not knowingly collect any personal data from children or other individuals who are not legally able to use our Services, and persons under the age of 13 are not permitted to create accounts. If we learn that we have collected the personal information of a child under the age of 13, we will take steps to delete the information as soon as possible, unless we are legally obligated to retain such data. Parents who believe that their child has submitted personal information to us and would like to have it deleted may contact us.

## Information Security

We work hard to keep your data safe. We use a combination of technical, administrative, and physical controls to maintain the security of your data. This includes using Transport Layer Security (TLS) and Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to encrypt, transmit and securely store sensitive information. No method of transmitting or storing data is completely secure, so if you have a security-related concern, please contact us.

## International Information Transfers

Answers in Genesis is a U.S.-based company (the U.S. ministry) with ministry affiliates in Canada (Canada ministry), the United Kingdom (the U.K. ministry), Australia (the Australia ministry), Latin America (the Latin America ministry), and Peru (the Peru ministry). We operate internationally through such ministry affiliates, which are responsible for controlling and processing information for Services on behalf of customers in those locations.

The U.S. ministry primarily stores U.S. customer information in the United States, and our ministry affiliates in Canada, the United Kingdom, Australia, Latin America, and Peru maintain their own customer account information in their respective locations. In order to facilitate our international operations, we may temporarily have access to information from customers in these other countries where our affiliates operate, for the purpose of facilitating Service requests, providing technical assistance, and for the purposes described in this Policy.

To the extent the U.S. ministry receives personal data relating to customers in an affiliate location, we generally transfer such information to such affiliates in order for them to facilitate the Service requests of those customers, and do not retain any records of personal data on those customers in the United States. To the extent the U.S. ministry receives and temporarily holds such information, we rely on multiple legal bases to lawfully transfer personal data to our affiliates. These include your consent and approved model contractual clauses, which require certain privacy and security protections.

If you are accessing or using our websites or Services in the United States or otherwise providing information to us, you are agreeing to the transfer of your personal information to the United States and other jurisdictions in which we or our affiliates operate.

Answers in Genesis is subject to the oversight of the US Federal Trade Commission and remains responsible for personal information that we transfer to others who process it on our behalf as described in the How Information is Shared section. Please note that the countries where we operate may have privacy and data protection laws that differ from, and are potentially less protective than, the laws of your country. You agree to this risk when you create an Answers in Genesis account, irrespective of which country you live in. If you later wish to withdraw your consent, you can contact us to request deletion of your account.

## Changes to This Policy

If we make changes to this Policy that we believe materially impact the privacy of your personal data, you will have an opportunity to review the revised policy before deciding if you would like to continue to use the Services. We will also post the updated Policy on this website, noting the effective date of any changes.

If you reside in the United States, then Answers in Genesis, Inc., a U.S. company in Kentucky, provides you with the Services. [Contact AiG–United States](https://answersingenesis.org/about/contact/)

If you reside in Canada, then Answers in Genesis-Canada, a ministry organization in Ontario, Canada, generally provides you with the Services. [Contact Answers in Genesis-Canada](https://answersingenesis.ca/contact-us/)

If you reside in Australia or New Zealand, then Answers in Genesis-Australia, a ministry organization in Queensland, Australia, generally provides you with the Services. [Contact Answers in Genesis-Australia/New Zealand](https://answersingenesis.com.au/contact-us/)

If you live in the European Economic Area, the United Kingdom, or Switzerland, then Answers in Genesis-UK/Europe, a company organized in the United Kingdom, generally provides you with the Services. As a resident of the European Economic Area, you may exercise your legal rights under GDPR and similar data privacy laws by submitting a [personal information inquiry](https://answersingenesis.org/forms/personal-information-inquiry/) to the Data Protection Officers of AiG–US, AiG–UK/Europe, and affiliated ministries. For other matters, you may [contact Answers in Genesis UK/Europe](https://answersingenesis.co.uk/contact-us/) through their website.

If you reside in Latin America, then Answers in Genesis-Latin America, a ministry organization in Mexico, generally provides you with the Services. [Contact Answers in Genesis-Latin America](https://answersingenesis.org/es/contactenos/)

If you reside in Peru, then Answers in Genesis-Peru, a ministry organization in Peru, generally provides you with the Services. [Contact Answers in Genesis-Peru](https://answersingenesis.org/es/contactenos/)

Last Updated: 5/24/2018
